<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on Michael Ladd (mjladd)</title>
    <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on Michael Ladd (mjladd)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 13:43:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://mjladd.github.io/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2000 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/2000-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 13:43:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/2000-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
While work was going well, I was still trying to find a school for a PhD program. I got accepted into what looked like a decent program and left work to live in Florida. My brother introduced me to &amp;lsquo;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&amp;rsquo; which was a huge influence on my thinking.
Reading List 2000
 Girlfriend in a Coma - Douglas Coupland The Imaginary Girlfriend - John Irving Catch 22 - Joseph Heller To Boulez and Beyond - Joan Peyser The Sheltering Sky - Paul Bowles The Crossing - Cormac McCarthy A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius - David Eggers Geeks - Jon Katz House of Leaves - Mark Z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1999 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1999-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 1999 13:42:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1999-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
1999 was full of changes. I had finished off the masters program in a year and a half. I had committed to working at a music camp over the summer where I consumed the entire David Foster Wallace collection. I also spent some time traveling and finally had to make a career decision. Although I was accepted into a PhD program, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t come up with the funds, so into IT I went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1998 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1998-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 1998 13:41:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1998-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
After graduation, I was offered a Teaching Assistantship. Looking back at only having read 13 books over an entire year is almost embarrassing.
Reading List 1998
 Architects of the Web - Robert Reid My Idea of Fun - Will Self Exegesis - Astro Teller Music Since 1945 - Elliot Schwartz Anton Von Webern - Malcom Hayes The Proud Highway - Hunter S. Thompson Digerati - John Brackman The Neon Bible - John Kennedy Toole High Fidelity - Nick Hornby American Pioneers: Ives to Cage and Beyond - Alan Rich Talking Music - William Duckworth Do I Come Here Often - Henry Rollins Solipsist - Henry Rollins  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1997 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1997-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1997 13:40:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1997-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
1997 was an insanely busy year. I spent most of the time preparing for my solo recital, as well as working three jobs at a time while maintaining a full course load. I was living in a great house that I never saw, and spent up to 50-60 hours a week at the recording studio.
Reading List 1997
 The Little Kingdom - Michael Moritz Being Digital - Nicholas Negroponte Ladies and Gentleman, Lenny Bruce - Albert Goldman Downsize This - Michael Moore Silicon Snake Oil - Clifford Stoll Takedown - Simormura and Markoff Masters of Deception - Slatalle and Quittner The Hacker Crackdown - Bruce Sterling The Fugitive Game - Jonathan Littman A Year With Swollen Appendicies - Brian Eno I Sing the Body Electric - Fred Moody Poloroids from the Dead - Douglas Coupland Tooth Imprints on a Corn Dog - Mark Leyner Elliot Carter: In Conversation with Enzo Restagno Random Acts of Sensless Violence - Jack Womack  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1996 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1996-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 1996 13:39:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1996-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
I purchased my first computer (Apple Performa) in 1996, and my book reading declined exponentially. I started reading more about technology than fiction.
Reading List 1996
 The Rachel Papers - Martin Amis Trout Fishing in America - Richard Brautigan The Stranger - Albert Camus The Road Ahead - Bill Gates Mishima - John Nathan True Story - Bill Maher Spike, Mike, Slackers, and Dykes - John Pierson Rush Limbaugh is a Big Fat Idiot - Al Franken The Grifters - Jim Thompson Microserfs - Douglas Coupland Insanely Great - Steve Levy Screams from the Balcony - Charles Bukowski The Tortilla Curtain - T.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1995 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1995-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 1995 13:38:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1995-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
I can&amp;rsquo;t remember what finally got me into Raymond Carver, but he&amp;rsquo;s by far my favorite short-story writer. I remember 1995 as being a very confusing time, and I went through a huge variety of writers that year.
Reading List 1995
 Short Cuts - Raymond Carver Feast of Snakes - Harry Crews No Minor Chords - Andre Previn Frank Zappa: Negative Dialects of Poodle Play - Ben Watson The Knockout Artist - Harry Crews Tracer - Frederic Barthelme Kentucky Ham - William S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1994 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1994-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 1994 13:34:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1994-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
1994 was more of the same, but I started diving into a large number of musician&amp;rsquo;s biographies. It was the first summer that I spent away from home in my first apartment. My roommate and I both worked in restaurants and took classes during the day. I would often hide out in the school library for the free air-conditioning.
Reading List 1994
 The Most Beautiful Woman in Town - Charles Bukowski The Job - William S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1993 12 31 Reading</title>
      <link>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1993-12-31-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 1993 18:19:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mjladd.github.io/reading/1993-12-31-reading/</guid>
      <description>Summary:
1993 was an incredible year for finally having the chance to read so many authors that I&amp;rsquo;ve only heard about. I remember spending my typical Friday evenings at college at the Library until it closed at 7:00 pm, and then heading home with a pile of books by Hunter Thompson, Hubert Selby, or Charles Bukowski. I would hole up in my dorm room with a fresh pot of coffee and read for four to five hours before heading out for more typical college fun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>